### Curriculum Vitae



Dhaka • Bangladesh • towfiqul.islam@selise.ch • (+880) 1823 923023

# **SUMMARY**

Experienced software engineer with a passion for working on web application development, web development and a solid record in programming languages along with DevOps and other tools. Technology & other tools knowledge: Java 7, Java 8, Java 11 (Spring Boot, Camel), Kotlin, PHP (Laravel), Bash, Python, C/C++, JavaScript (JQuery), My SQL, VS Code, PHPStorm, IntelliJ IDEA, Sublime Text, Workbench, MongoDB Compass.

Experience with DevOps: Docker, AWS, Linux Terminal

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### **SELISE (Secure Link Services Ltd.)**

Software and Consultancy AG

Nov2021 - Present

# **Software Engineer**

- Responsible for defining & developing software for tasks associated.
- Software design and development and ensure software quality.
- Develop enhancements to existing products.
- Collaborate in a team environment to share best practices. Implement process improvements.
- Backend engineer developing microservice using Springboot & Kotlin
- Converted a project from Java to Kotlin.

# **Exabyting**

Dhaka. Bangladesh

Dec 2019 - Nov 2021

### **Software Engineer**

- Developed various Govt and Private Web Applications and Services.
- Planned development cycle and collected requirements for developing software.
- Managed three-member groups and delivered tasks within the deadline.
- Worked with bKash Limited as Partner Team with their Solution Engineering Team.
- Learned software design patterns, clean coding, communication, and taking ownership.
- Work in Agile/Scrum development process.
- Review and Analyze Project requirement Document.

- Prepared release notes and conducted deployment.
- Demo presentation on-demand.

## TechServe4U

Michigan, USA

May 2021 - Oct2021

# **Java Software Engineer**

- Developed various Web Applications and Services for testing applications.
- Planned development cycle and collected requirements for developing test software.
- Prepared positive and negative test cases depending on requirements.
- Supported others on Java Programming.

### Inflack Limited.

IT & Services

Sept 2019 - Nov 2019

### **Software Engineering Intern**

 Inflack, is an experienced and passionate group of developers, designers, and project managers. Inflack believes best-in-class digital projects require technology that perfectly supports the design and relies on the right tools for the job, not a one-size-fits-all tech stack.

## **Presidency International School**

Chittagong Bangladesh

Oct 2018 - Aug 2019

### **CS Teacher and Competitive Programming Coach**

- Programming Contest Trainer, Club Convener, and Various Program
  Coordinator. Taught C++ and Python Languages in the context of a
  Programming Contest along with Basic Algorithms and Data
  Structures.
- Arranged various offline and online contests for the students'

### **AWARDS**

### **Team Award as Coach**

IIUC IUPC 2017, my team CJC\_TEAM\_1971 Ranked 2nd Position.

Programming Contest 2018, my team CJC\_TEAM\_1971 Ranked 5th position.

### **ACM Profiles**

### 5th Position on CSE Week Programming Contest 2016.

Participated in the divisional onsite contest: IIUC IUPC 2015,2016, USTC IUPC 2016 Solved 500+ problems in various online judges.

Virtual Judge ID: UVA: 448714, CF: laziestcoder, HR: Laziest\_Coder

### **PROJECTS**

### **Currency Converter**

A centralized currency converter service that provides real-time currency rates and conversions from any currency to any currency. It also provides historical currency rates with precisions along with options of graphical views. This widget is especially relevant for financial portals, services, or any other application as required. Technology: Kotlin

#### Inventex

This project processes some financial documents and provides a proxy route system. Technology: JAVA (Camel), Kafka, Active MQ

### **Bkash Agent App**

bKash Agent App, which is one of the most popular and financial apps for bKash Agents. Agent App

Middleware is a service that supports the Agent App to be functional. It also depends on other internal services. Implemented Pay Bill service into bKash Agent App. It is one of the core products of bKash Limited. Technology: JAVA(Spring-Boot), API, DynamoDB, AWS, Firebase

# **Airtime Management System**

An Internal Web Application of bKash Limited. Implemented basic main REST APIs, maker checker approval flow, and Email notification. Integrated log-back config, scheduler with async methodology and feign client. Technology: JAVA(Spring-Boot), API, JS, Oracle

## **Saving DPS**

An Internal Web Application of bKash Limited. A service for bKash App which allows customers to open a DPS. Technology: JAVA (Spring-Boot), API, JS, MySQL, AWS

#### **MULTIBANK**

An Internal Web Application of bKash Limited. Implemented SFTP inbound/outbound, Configurable Email notification with async methodology, maker checker approval flow, and log-back integration. Technology: JAVA(Spring-Boot), API, JQuery, MySQL, Spring-Integration

#### **PREVENTO**

It's an app where users provide information - gender, age, height, weight, diagnosed illnesses, risk factors, and the app will create a personalized health care plan. The app will provide tasks each month and Clients of selected medical partners write a message to a doctor and get an answer. Technology: PHP(Laravel), API, JQuery, MySQL, AWS, Google Analytics, Firebase.

### **SKILLS**

## **Programming Language**

Java 7, Java 8, Java 11 (Spring Boot, Camel), Kotlin, PHP (Laravel), Bash, Python, C/C++, JavaScript (JQuery)

### **DevOps**

Docker, Jenkins, AWS, CLI

### **IDE & Other Tools**

Intellij IDEA, PHPStorm. VS Code, Sublime Text, MySQL Workbench, MongoDB Compass

#### Server

Apache, Tomcat, GlassFish

### **Database**

Spring Data, JPA, Hibernate, Eloquent, SQL, MySQL, MariaDB, Oracle, DynamoDB, MongoDB, PostgreSQL

### **Testing Tools**

Postman, JUnit, Rest Assured, TestNg

## **Development Tool**

Feign Client, Rest Template, Maven, Gradle, Git, Composer, JIRA, Agile Methodologies (Scrum), Google Analytics, Firebase, Swagger, Active MQ

#### OS

Ubuntu, CentOS

### **EDUCATION**

#### 2014-2019

Chittagong, Bangladesh Bachelor's of Science in CSE, International Islam University, Chittagong

### LANGUAGES

Bengali (Native), English (Fluent)